A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1963-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1963-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.671
This collection consists of 23,400 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 6 September 1967.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Records, 1963-1964
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Adams Papers (see also Madison Papers) 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - Applicants 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - General (for Admissions Policy on Out-of-State students see Student Costs and Enrollment) 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Admissions Reports 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Panel on ROTC Affairs 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Air Force and Air Force ROTC 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Chapters Planned 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Chattanooga Chapter 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Houston Chapter 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Memphis Chapter 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Roanoke Chapter 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Savannah Chapter 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni-Fund (see also Alumni - Medical Alumni and Public Relations, meeting of all fund-raising groups) 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - University Club of Washington 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni News 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Speeches (see speeches) 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Architecture 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Architecture - Museum of Fine Arts 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Architecture - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 3)
  - Army 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Army - general 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J. A. G.) School Building 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Army - ROTC 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Art (see also Architecture - Museum of Fine Arts) 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Art Commission 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Membership with S.U.A. 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Circular Letters 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Astronomy 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - Invitations to Games, Board of Visitors, State Officials, etc. 1963-1964 (Box 5)
  - Athletics - A.C.C. 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - N.C.A.A. 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - 3 - 2 - 2 Committee 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Finances 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - General 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: Clemson Game - Commonwealth Day/Band Day, 26 October 1963 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: Duke Game, 28 September 1963 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: South Carolina Game - Homecoming, 19 October 1963 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: William and Mary, 9 November 1963 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Atlantic Council of the U. S. 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - Atomic Energy Commission 1963-1964 (Box 6)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - "Bo - Bz" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Berkeley, Francis L., Jr. 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Biology (see special file for Biophysics) 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Biology - Blandy Farm 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Biophysics 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Budget Office - Capital Outlay 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Budget - Director 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Budget - Operating Budget 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Budget Requests 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Building Program (see also Department or Division concerned) 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Progress Reports 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Bureau of Public Administration 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Calendar for Deans 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Calendar of Events 1963-1964 (Box 8)
  - Catholic Center 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Cavalier Daily 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Chancellor for Community Colleges 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry - Chairmanship 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry Building 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Children's Rehabilitation Center (see also Rehabilitation Center) 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Civic Beautification 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Civil Rights 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Civil Defenses 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Classics 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - Building Program 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - Monthly Reports 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - College Entrance Examination Board (see Admissions) 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Commerce - General 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Commerce - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Commission on Higher Education Facilities 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Administrative 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Admissions (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Arboretum Advisory (see also Blandy Farm) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Architectural Advisory (see also Army - J.A.G. School Building) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Athletic Advisory (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm Advisory 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Calendar of events (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Calendar and Scheduling 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Cemetery (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Chapel 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Chemistry Building (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley Advisory (see also Clinch Valley College) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Community Colleges Advisory (see also Chancellor) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Community Colleges Building 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Computer Center 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Special Committee on Deans 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Dormitory 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Dormitory Counselors (see also Housing) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Extension (see General Studies, School of ) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Fellowship Awards (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Field House (see also University Hall) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Fine Arts (Internal and External) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Foreign Nationals (see Foreign Student) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Fraternities (see also Fraternities) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Graduate 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Graduate Degrees in Summer (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Housing 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Institutional Analysis 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Library (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Long-Range Planning (Dissolved - folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Married Student Housing (see also Copely Hill) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Master Plan 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Medical Board of Hospital 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biological Station (see Biology - Mountain Lake) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Names for Buildings 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Objects of Art 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Orientation 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Page-Barbour and Richard Lectures 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Patrick-Henry Advisory 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Processions 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Public Occasions (see also Finals) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Public Relations (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Registration 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Research (see also Research) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment (see also Student Aid) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarships (see Fellowhsips and Scholarships - Rhodes Scholarships) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Space Astronomy 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Special Lectures (see also Lectures) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Student Activities 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Student Health 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Committee on Students 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Summer Session (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Teacher Education (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Traffic Control 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Tree (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Committee on Undergraduates (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Press 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Records (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Union (folder empty) (see also Newcomb Hall) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review Advisory (see Virginia Quarterly Review) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Wilson Gee Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Comptroller 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Computer Cener 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Construction Scineces Institute 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Cooper, Walden 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Copely Hill (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Council of Southern Universities (see also Southern Fellowships Fund) 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Darden, C. W., Jr. 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Deans Luncheon 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Economics 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Education 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Education - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Education - Rehabilitation Center (see Rehabilitation Center) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Educational Aid for State Employees 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Educational RESEARCH, Division of 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Educational T.V. 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Endowment Fund (Alumni Board of Trustees) 1963-1964 (Box 12)
  - Endowment Fund - Board of Visitors Consolidated (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - General 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - Pratt Fund 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Enrollment 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - English 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty (see also Faculty Tenure) 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty - General 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty Orientation Program and Reception 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty Tenure (see also University Tenure) 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Academic Faculty 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - General 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Departmental Chairmen 1963-1964 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Committees 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "A - G" 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "H - M" 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "N - S" 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "T - Z" 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Faulkner Foundation 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Faulkner House (see also Buildings and Roads, Names of - Permanent File) 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Federal Legislation 1963-1964 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Cross 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - DuPont Regional 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Love 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Finals 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Ford Foundation (see also 3 Year Masters Program - Graduate Arts and Sciences) (see also Jefferson Papers and Madison Papers) 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Affairs 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Foreign Student Advisor (see also Student Affairs) 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Founder's Day 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Fraternities 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Assembly (see also Legislative Program; Budget, Legislative Program and Special Files; Student Costs; and also Budget Requests) 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Studies, School of 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Studies - Branches Proposed 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Studies - Madison 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Studies - Northern Virginia Center 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry Branch 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Geography (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Geology 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - George Mason College 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - George Mason College - Building Program 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - George Mason College - Monthly Reports 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - George Mason College - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Gilmer Hall 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Governor's Office (see also Student Costs) 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences - 3-Years Masters Program 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration 1963-1964 (Box 17)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Edward B. Gordon 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Sponsors (see also Public Relations - meeting of all fund-raising group) 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - "Ha - Hk" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - "Ho - Hz" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Haight, Henry C., Jr. 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - Highway Department 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - History 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Honor System and Honor Committee 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Honors Program 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Housing (see also Housing Committee and Faulkner House) 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Housing - Married Student Housing and Dormitory Construction (see Copely Hill) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Institute of Early American History and Culture 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Institute of International Education 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Institutional Analysis re: Connor as Director 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Institutional Analysis - Candidates for Directorship 1963-1964 (Box 19)
  - Institutional Analysis, Office of 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Institutional Self-Study 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "A" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "B" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "C" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "D" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "E" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "F" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "G" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "H" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "I" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "J" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "K" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "L" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "M" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "N" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "O" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "P" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "Q" (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "R" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "S" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "T" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "U" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "V" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "W" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1963-1964 (Box 20)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Thomas Jefferson Center 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Thomas Jefferson Center 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Thomas Jefferson - Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Jefferson Papers (see also Adams, Madison Papers) (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Jefferson Society (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Joint Office of Institutional Research 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Law - General 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Law - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Legal Matters 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Legal - Estates, Deeds 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Legal - Estates, Old (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Legislative Program 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Liberal Arts 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Library 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Library - Building Committee 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Life Science Building 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - "M - Me" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 22)
  - Madison Papers (see also Adams Papers and Jefferson Papers) 1963-1964 (Box 23)
  - Marine Science 1963-1964 (Box 23)
  - Markle Foundation 1963-1964 (Box 23)
  - Mary Washington College - Building Program 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Mary Washington College - Financial 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Mary Washington College - General 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Mary Washington College - Personnel 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Mathematics 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Medical Center - General 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Medical Center - Hospital 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Medical Center - Medical Board of Hospital (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical Center - Hospital - Monthly Statistical Reports 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical Center - Hospital - Reports on Current Operations 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical Center - Hospital - Rehabilitation Center (see Rehabilitation Center) 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical School - Finances 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical School - General 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical School - Personnel, "A - G" 1963-1964 (Box 25)
  - Medical School - Personnel, "H - M" 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - Medical Center - Personnel, "N - Z" 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - Modern Languages 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - Monroe, James, Memorial Foundation and Library 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - Monroe Papers 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - Music 1963-1964 (Box 26)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (see also Virginia Assoc. Res. Center and Research and Trng. Funds Policy) 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - National Defense Education Act 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - National Historical Publications Committee 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - National Science Foundation (see Marine Science for application for graduate level Research facilities development grant) 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - National Science Foundation (Institutional Grant for Science) 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - NATO Visiting Professors Program 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - Navy - General 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - Navy - ROTC 1963-1964 (Box 27)
  - Newcomb Hall 1963-1964 (Box 28)
  - Newcomen Society 1963-1964 (Box 28)
  - News Letter 1963-1964 (Box 28)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 28)
  - Office Information 1963-1964 (Box 28)
  - Office Supplies (including Travel Vouchers, Invoices - General Store purchases, etc.) 1963-1964 (Box 28)
  - "P - Ph" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - "Pi - Pz" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Parking Legislation 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Personnel - Richmond and Local Offices (see also Educational Aid for State Employees) (See Medicine - Clinical Personnel. See Police Survey for Classification of Security Director) 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Philosophy 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Photographs 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Physics (see special file for Biophysics) 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Planning Department 9see also individual building programs) 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Political Science 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Possible Donors 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Possible Donors - Insurance 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - President's Council (see also Tax Study Commission) 1963-1964 (Box 29)
  - Psychology (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Public Education, Committee on 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Public Relations 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Purchasing 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Questionnaires and Inquiries (see also Office of Institutional Analysis) 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Radiation Protection 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Radio 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Raven Society 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Recommendation, Letters of 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Registrar 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Registrar - Student Enrollment 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Rehabilitation Center 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Religion 1963-1964 (Box 30)
  - Research 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Research and Training Funds Policy (Includes Committee on) 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Research and Training Funds Policy (extra Mimeo'd material, April 1963 - July 1963) 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Rifle Range 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Salaries 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Security Force (see also Police Survey) 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Senate, University 1963-1964 (Box 31)
  - Seven Society 1963-1964 (Box 32)
  - Sociology and Anthropology (folder empty) 1963-1964 (Box 32)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (se also Institutional Self-Study) 1963-1964 (Box 32)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1963-1964 (Box 32)